Martin," he felt how impossible it would be to tell these two
Martin Decoud was angry with himself. All he saw and heard going
Martin Decoud, the dilettante in life, imagined himself to derive
Martin Decoud called out from the lighter, "Au revoir, messieurs,
Martin," he went on in a keen but friendly whisper, "I am so
Martin," he said, moodily. "There are very few things that I am
Martin Decoud, the imaginative materialist, was able to do in the
Martin Decoud had admitted him to a sort of intimacy, so that he
