that American sailor worked for some months on board a schooner,
The fellow had actually managed to steal a lighter with silver,
dusk, gossip half-forgotten, faces grown dim. . . . Perhaps,
a twilight country which was to become the province of Sulaco,
course, my venerated friend, the late Don Jose Avellanos,
I hope that my accuracy will be trusted. In justice to myself,
As to their own histories I have tried to set them down,
Aristocracy and People, men and women, Latin and Anglo-Saxon,
contrasted men, both captured by the silver of the San Tome Mine,
satisfaction to think that in my very young days there must,
he hardly knows by what or by whom, he is still of the People,
Nostromo the Man of the People are the artisans of the New Era,
had perhaps more glow and less serenity in her soul than Antonia,
filial devotion before the monument of Don Jose Avellanos, and,
enormous semi-circular and unroofed temple open to the ocean,
its forbidden treasures. The common folk of the neighbourhood,
donkey to carry for them a bundle of dry sticks, a water-skin,
about to set. They had watched the strange portent with envy,
like a sinster pirate-ship of the air, hove-to above the horizon,
cavern. In its vastness your ship floats unseen under your feet,
grove of orange trees--lies between the mountains and the plain,
inlets in an iron-bound coast--like Esmeralda, for instance,
her captain and the painted and gilt luxuriousness of her saloon,
whereas the Ganymede was fitted out mainly for cattle transport,
And as they seldom failed to account for the smallest package,
rarely lost a bullock, and had never drowned a single passenger,
then the whole length of the jetty; it had been a desperate dash,
at the other end with the Company's flag at the stern. Sticks,
and temple, made by a razor-blade fastened to a stick--a weapon,
"These gentlemen," he would say, staring with great solemnity,
a--a--er--respectable man. They would have pounded me to death,
terror of all the thieves in the town. We were infested,
wasn't one that hadn't heard of Nostromo. As to the town leperos,
the lives of these gentlemen. Captain Mitchell, on his part,
never left them till he had seen them collapse, panting,
well under their Capataz. An outcast lot of very mixed blood,
little girls on that great plain?  So, barricading every opening,
his divinities; but he tolerated "superstition" in women,
fled early that morning at the first sounds of the riot,
the house; a preference for which they were in no way to blame,
momentary shelter behind the wall made the darkness of the room,
children clinging to her, one on each side, gasped for breath,
House. "If I see smoke rising over there," he thought to himself,
small band of Italian workmen in that direction, which, indeed,
"It is what I say. You have no heart--and you have no conscience,
each other to the pursuit.  He put himself at their head, crying,
maternal exaltation.  Behind her the wall was dazzlingly white,
Then Signora Teresa, all in black, issuing from another door,
himself. The Indian girls, with hair like flowing black manes,
sunshine, a strong smell of burnt onions hung in the drowsy heat,
settle at last in Sulaco after wandering from town to town,
Italian drivers saluted him from the foot-plate with raised hand,
violent game played upon the plain by dwarfs mounted and on foot,
in all its details at once; he shaded his eyes with his hand,
the line snorting, kicking, squealing in a compact, piebald,
She said all this quickly, with great assurance, in an animated,
Nostromo; but as to his daughters, the severity of his temper,
had taken part, on great plains, on the banks of immense rivers,
heroically with his negroes at the fording of the Boyana. He,
the general. Later, in Italy, he, with the rank of lieutenant,
Republic; he was one of the four fugitives who, with the general,
carelessness of a condottiere, it was a puritanism of conduct,
abruptly with a jerk of the head and a movement of the arm,
With their handsome, bronzed, lean faces, shiny black ringlets,
the chief of police, some broad-faced, brown little gentleman,
table. He pointed to one of the bottles on the shelf; Giorgio,
himself steered the cargo lighter, all draped with flags, which,
men, caballeros of pure descent, with small hands and feet,
The head of the chairman of the railway board (from London),
mountains which he himself had traversed in an old diligencia,
fertile territory--all these aristocratic old Spanish families,
so-called agent, evidently a man of culture and ability, seemed,
that the President-Dictator would make the journey. He regretted,
descent. Indeed, it was said that he and his brother, orphans,
They gave him his dinner in a stone hut like a cubical boulder,
The man who, perhaps disturbed by the proximity of the voices,
the habit of calling Nostromo.  And indeed, taciturn and ready,
Cargadores" which was to bring Nostromo into personal contact,
their relation to throw doubt on that statement, unless, indeed,
conspiracy which was betrayed and, as people expressed it,
Born in the country, as his father before him, spare and tall,
church and shot by the order of the barbarous Unionist general,
Perpetual President, famed for his ruthless and cruel tyranny,
ancestral Goulds--liberators, explorers, coffee planters,
reining in his steed on the pedestal above the sleeping leperos,
moustaches, would decline to discuss them at all. Once, however,
was invariably followed by a slight shudder and a low,
Then giving up the empty cup into his young friend's hand,
stateliness of ancient days lingered between the four high,
smooth walls, tinted a delicate primrose-colour; and Mrs. Gould,
cloud of muslin and lace before a slender mahogany table,
clemency.  The mine, which by every law, international, human,
and divine, reverts now to the Government as national property,
pay a beggarly money compensation to the families of the victims,
of this affair, though no doubt deeply meditated in the closet,
mine; it was a wild, inaccessible, and rocky gorge of the Sierra,
where vestiges of charred timber, some heaps of smashed bricks,
was a man to whom, in years gone by, Mr.  Gould had,
unfortunately, declined to grant some small pecuniary assistance,
function of a judge. Now, after reaching his exalted position,
to get the matter dropped. It would have been useless.  Indeed,
of something she could not accomplish. The friend of Mr. Gould,
death of Guzman Bento. His experience had taught him that,
silver mine in the Sulaco province of the Republic of Costaguana,
pay heavy fines for neglecting to work the mine, he reported,
detect this secret mood which governed the profoundly sensible,
Gould visited no mines, though they went together in a carriage,
inconsequent retort, which he accepted as perfectly sagacious,
She went very pale under the roses of her big straw hat, gloved,
its misery. He caught hold of her hand, raised it to his lips,
and at that she dropped her parasol to pat him on the cheek,
curve of her hat-brim, very small in her simple, white frock,
buildings, of stone walls; and in mid-air the sound of a bell,
her power without detracting from his dignity. That slight girl,
overweighted by great coils of hair; with a rather large mouth,
experienced woman. She was, before all things and all flatteries,
down at her, and at once fell a prey to distress, incertitude,
very sound of the bell.  When her feet touched the ground again,
one foot into a dry and dusty ditch, picked up the open parasol,
They turned back, and after she had slipped her hand on his arm,
once, as a small boy, with my dear mother, for a whole year,
in a remote and savage district, and the San Tome Concession,
the eagerness of youth for a strange life, for great distances,
The words it pronounces have the value of acts of integrity,
own words--have been for them "something of a monster." However,
of water, and the fat coachman sat muffled up on the edge,
their three hats. Captain Mitchell, the fourth, in attendance,
ferociously, "Viva Costaguana!" then called twice mellifluously,
bookcase, with glass doors, was full of books; but in the other,
firearms: Winchester carbines, revolvers, a couple of shot-guns,
Then, surprised at her husband's silence, she raised her eyes,
spurs, and, twisting his moustache with both hands, horizontally,
"Ah, yes! The religion of silver and iron. He's a very civil man,
"The best of my feelings are in your keeping, my dear," he said,
existence as an enterprise, giving a return to men--to strangers,
position. You seem to think this perfectly natural--do you? Well,
Mrs. Gould, an orphan from early childhood and without fortune,
she had not learned that they were desirable.  On the other hand,
wealth well to the fore; but he brought it forward as a means,
word for everything: industry, trade, law, journalism, art,
"Our consuls get their mouths stopped with them," he continued,
right.  The main question for us is whether the second partner,
iron, glass, and blocks of stone at the corner of two streets,
envelope) was taken unopened straight into the great man's room,
last something silly, and was ashamed of his folly; others,
Republic of Costaguana, lock, stock, and barrel.  But, in fact,
"Viva Costaguana!" he shrieked, with intense self-assertion, and,
The allusion was not to the point.  Don Jose was a dear good man,
combined unexpectedly well with his English get-up. He came back,
than he meant to go; and with the roundabout logic of emotions,
praise enough dear Carlos's tact and courage. His English,
This might have been less or more than the truth.  Mrs. Gould,
Costaguanera could have done. In her travel-worn riding habit,
little cavalcade. Two mozos de campo, picturesque in great hats,
brown muleteer, sitting his long-eared beast very near the tail,
legs thrust far forward, the wide brim of his hat set far back,
green young crops, plains, woodland, and gleams of water,
the trudging files of burdened Indians taking off their hats,
coast towns, a great land of plain and mountain and people,
softly in the moonlight under the orange trees of the courtyards,
she could hear stories of political outrage; friends, relatives,
man's load resting above his head on the top of the low mud wall,
"Poor Costaguana! Before, it was everything for the Padres,
Sulaco mail with his own hand), and a great man of another sort,
as a cafe waiter in Madrid; but his talents must have been great,
"Exquisite, delicious!" he murmured; while Charles Gould waited,
"I have already sent a memorial," said Charles Gould, steadily,
his toes, and for ten minutes, almost without drawing breath,
man with a solemn inclination of the head and the words,
timid by his horrible experiences of Guzman Bento's time),
Moraga family possessing extensive estates in the Sulaco Valley,
found for him whenever he took the road. Very brown and wooden,
snows of Higuerota gleamed pale over the town on a yet black sky,
with the butt of a heavy revolver at the doors of low pulperias,
street and snarling low curses. At sunrise Captain Mitchell,
abandoned convents behind the rows of sombre green cypresses,
You turned in from the street, as if entering a secluded orchard,
light, Don Pepe moving his long moustaches as he spelt his way,
two shifts, stripped to linen drawers and leather skull-caps,
leading to the bottom of the gorge. It was deep; and, far below,
himself, or perhaps some grown girl, the pride of the family,
And they would laugh a little with astonishment and scorn,
the charge from Mrs. Gould, and lived in the hospital building,
worked in harmony.  Father Roman, dried-up, small, alert,
presbytery. Near by, a long, low, dark building, steeple-roofed,
Gobernador would go off, holding up his sabre against his side,
provoked instantly a great shrilling of responding whistles,
for a moment with the two motionless serenos before him, and,
which he believed himself entitled. It had been promised to him,
Hernandez, the robber, had been an inoffensive, small ranchero,
the little towns on the Campo, driving a pack mule before him,
with two revolvers in his belt, go straight to the shop or store,
been put upon his head; even attempts had been made,
ambitious of the glory of having reduced the famous Hernandez,
unsuspecting followers  They came, indeed, at the appointed time,
let their presence be known by a general discharge of firearms,
upon the National Army. The highest civil official of Tonoro,
of the country with its story of oppression, inefficiency,
"If it had not been for the lawless tyranny of your Government,
chief of the police, the chief of the customs, the general, all,
Tome mine, working for a good cause, had his moments of anxiety,
soul," with an air of profound self-satisfaction which, somehow,
silent, with the lines deepened on his English, ruddy,
advice, with his manuscript of a historical work on Costaguana,
world"; these three, and also Dona Emilia amongst them, gracious,
imagining himself to be in the thick of things. The good man,
ingots packed in boxes of stiff ox-hide with plaited handles,
a while; the heavy cattle stood up breast deep in the grass,
The early sunshine glowed on the delicate primrose, pale pink,
pale blue fronts of the big houses with all their gates shut yet,
of her muslin wrapper. With a smile to her husband's single,
friendly sign the salute of the galloping Don Pepe, the stiff,
more fatuous imbecility, plenty of cruelty and suffering still,
him from Moraga if you can--the agent of the King of Sulaco,
of the San Tome Administration in Sta. Marta (a polished,
Vincente Ribiera, a man of culture and of unblemished character,
good faith and order in public life. So much the better, then,
construction of the National Central Railway.  Good faith, order,
elbows with the other foreign diplomat, a dark man with a quiet,
The Excellentissimo was on his legs. He said only a few words,
Mrs. Gould, listening to the mellow, slightly mournful voice,
looking at this rotund, dark, spectacled face, at the short body,
that followed the speech, General Montero raised a pair of heavy,
before, and had hardly ever seen the sea except from a distance),
understood by a sort of instinct the advantage his surly,
a strangely rasping, soulless ring. He floundered, lowering,
An enormous national flag of Costaguana, diagonal red and yellow,
Now and then a lot of rockets, swishing upwards invisibly,
Don Vincente Ribiera made a few steps under the deck-awning,
of the sabre standing upright between his legs. The white plume,
for a moment. "More in memory of those who have died," he added,
embroidered ends, the silver plates on headstall and saddle,
He turned his horse slowly, and paced on between the booths,
eddied and pushed before the doors of the high-roofed building,
emotion, seemed to draw Nostromo on to its source, while a man,
wrapped up in a faded, torn poncho, walked by his stirrup, and,
the blue woollen skirt, with all the fullness gathered in front,
"Because I don't love thee any more," said Nostromo,
went on without a pause. "But if you love her as much as that,
"No," said Nostromo, looking into her uplifted, begging eyes,
curiosity of the eyes, then flung back to the stirrup, tiptoeing,
"Stand on my foot," he commanded the girl, who, suddenly subdued,
There were shouts of laughter and applause at this witty freak,
The circle had broken up, and the lordly Capataz de Cargadores,
and a half later, it was unofficially, over the mountain tracks,
"It was history--history, sir! And that fellow of mine, Nostromo,
The harbour was busy, too, with the traffic in railway material,
Captain Mitchell, feeling more and more in the thick of history,
was incarnated in himself, and his adversaries, the Federalists,
were the supreme sinners, objects of hate, abhorrence, and fear,
skeletons, loaded with irons, covered with dirt, with vermin,
with raw wounds, all men of position, of education, of wealth,
drink of muddy water in pitiful accents. Don Jose Avellanos,
the left breast of a lieutenant's uniform--would follow,
Bento, usually full of fanciful fears and brooding suspicions,
Miss Avellanos, born in Europe and educated partly in England,
was a tall, grave girl, with a self-possessed manner, a wide,
Avellanos desired passionately for his country: peace,
nations." In this last phrase the Minister Plenipotentiary,
most useful at a distance, in Sulaco. His name, his connections,
Gould had drawn the sword, so now, the times being changed,
Vincente, a doctor of philosophy from the Cordova University,
portent in boots, and with a sabre, made meaningless now at last,
explained afterwards that the initiative, and even the very text,
The brothers were organizing an army, gathering malcontents,
the Cordillera and the capital. Monterist publications, however,
defence of the Five-Year Mandate of regeneration. The petition,
(perhaps looted in some village store), covered with the crabbed,
range afar from the waste lands protecting his fastness,
knows--what do I say?--this whole South American continent knows,
neither his part, nor his inclination, nor his policy. His part,
the side of Mrs. Gould in the landau, with his fine, old,
clean-shaven face of a uniform tint as if modelled in yellow wax,
with the open palm of his hand upon the knob of a flexible cane,
The shirt collar, cut low in the neck, the big bow of his cravat,
the short, curly, golden beard did not conceal his lips, rosy,
Maria Heredia. In other moments he had, to pass the time,
clowning of a harlequin by the spangles of a motley costume,
bondholders.  Really, if what I am told in my letters is true,
This letter, in Antonia's handwriting, was signed by Don Jose,
grounds, and privately opened his heart to his talented god-son,
Minister, Montero, a mistrusted member of the Ribiera Government,
Avellanos had left Europe for good, as a tall girl of sixteen,
received regularly from Costaguana, the name of their friends,
familias principales. Privately Don Jose, still shaken and weak,
Decoud. Alas! our worst fears have been realized," he moaned,
self-forgetful in its lively readiness of attention. Because,
half-educated negroes and wholly penniless lawyers. Then,
confronting with a sort of urbane effrontery Mrs.  Gould's gaze,
Even Senor Moraga in Sta. Marta had not been able to find one,
the Plaza. It was next to Anzani's great emporium of boots,
silks, ironware, muslins, wooden toys, tiny silver arms, legs,
heads, hearts (for ex-voto offerings), rosaries, champagne,
black silk patch over one eye. His other eye, small and deep-set,
on a furious ride to the harbour. But Mrs.  Gould bent forward,
division, commanding in chief the Occidental Military district,
tales of extraordinary night rides, encounters with wild bulls,
struggles with crocodiles, adventures in the great forests,
horses, pistols, and accoutrements, to the very epaulettes,
that money, too, when his only remark, as he rose calmly, was,
incessant difficulties of costume caused by the anxious lenders,
exaggerated lamentations that if the general were passed over,
positively fascinated by the long drooping nose, the peaked chin,
without any equivalent, as far as he could see. He had not,
us, we shall grow rich, one and all, like so many Englishmen,
gig was awaiting the general at the boat steps; and Barrios,
invisible wire far into the great campo--like a slender,
The cafe window of the Albergo d'ltalia Una was full of sunburnt,
in double quick time, like bersaglieri; they looked well fed,
yet we used to prevail against the oppressor," he concluded,
nervous haste, also in English.  "You should not jest like this,
engineer was utterly in the dark. "Great what?" he muttered,
Avellanos, who had returned to his immobility. "It is only you,
but what on earth had come to Mrs.  Gould? She said, "Go on,
have the naked truth from the mouth of that child. You are right,
scream of warlike triumph. And it was all like a fleeting vision,
steam-whistle for the brakes had stopped, a series of hard,
battering shocks, mingled with the clanking of chain-couplings,
the empty town. On the ancient pavement, laid out in patterns,
springs of the Parisian-built landau, had pulled up to a walk,
masonry with bunches of grass growing at the top, and a grey,
above him; the old coachman, with his broad back filling a short,
a treasure-house, and all these people are breaking into it,
Mrs. Gould said, "Oh, this is unjust!" And Antonia interjected,
towards Charles Gould, who was bowing before her; while Decoud,
phrase, "The greatest enthusiasm," pronounced by Mrs. Gould,
damask curtain, falling straight from the broad brass cornice,
hid him partly from the room. He folded his arms on his breast,
saddles.  She was a woman of most distinguished family, proud,
dignified old lady, respected and admired by the first families,
She made an almost imperceptible negative movement of her head,
still staring across the street at the Avellanos's house, grey,
remained still, her eyes fixed upon the house of the Avellanos,
The value of a sentence is in the personality which utters it,
"I have the greatest tenderness for your father," he began,
the houses, lit up vaguely by the glimmer of street lamps,
"Behold the illustrious Capataz de Cargadores," said Decoud,
Liberator Bolivar had said in the bitterness of his spirit,
has--you know, like a sort of avenging spirit. He gives one look,
in the shade of a wall. Never let go his elbow for a moment,
"Any slight sign of favour from a relative of yours is welcome,
him, too, our Padre Corbelan.  The idea of political honour,
higher officials of the province, engineers of the railway,
news of the war and the last proclamation of the rebel Montero,
argument," he said to Antonia. "I have invented this definition,
shattered against Antonia's gravity. She irritated him as if she,
Gould's habit to withdraw quietly into a little drawing-room,
especially her own, next to the great sala. She had risen, and,
over her, relating slowly, without the slightest gesture,
"I am going to cling to mine to the end, Antonia," he answered,
days, half naked, carrying a bullock-hide shield, and, no doubt,
possibly had not realized what a tough priest he was. Meantime,
country had known for years. The Sulaco police knew, of course,
Then he went away moodily to sit in an armchair, smoking a long,
the son of his own country nor of any other," he continued,
diplomatist--the life and soul of the party--he seemed gigantic,
party, or, rather, its mouthpiece, the "son Decoud" from Paris,
strange, anxious whine the sonority of the Spanish language,
plain man could carry on his little business now in the country,
the smoke of my cigar into the air through his nostrils, he said,
hook-nosed man from Esmeralda, anxious about the export of hides,
the San Tome mine, and then, perhaps, later on, other mines,
The engineer-in-chief, looking in at the door of the empty sala,
"I mean, going to the roots, you know," the engineer explained,
The engineer-in-chief whistled low. "A pretty game," he said,
then"--pursued the Administrador of the San Tome mine--"but then,
he is very far away, you know, and, as they say in this country,
The engineer's appreciative laugh died away down the stairs,
from the first, there was really any possible way back.  And,
"I will leave you; I've a slight headache. The heat, the dust,
bravado. "We have disturbed a good many snakes in that Paradise,
"Who's there?" she asked, in a startled voice. "Is that you,
Basilio?" She looked in, and saw Martin Decoud walking about,
But, even as he said this, he had obviously given up his search,
"What is it, Don Martin?" asked Mrs. Gould. And then she added,
conceal his agitation. "Pray Jack don't distress yourself Jack. No, really,
"No, senor," said behind Mrs. Gould the soft voice of Basilio,
Decoud, exchanging a steady stare with Mrs. Gould, added,
numbers in such times as these. And even if it were true? Well,
believe I am a true hijo del pays, a true son of the country,
"You don't seem convinced," Decoud went on again in French. "Say,
A puzzled look came upon Mrs. Gould's face, and Decoud,
"Nothing," answered Decoud, firmly. "But, then, don't you see,
of general pardon which I have seen, my name, with a few others,
is much better for him to convince himself in his own way. And,
bandit was the living,breathing example of cruelty, injustice,
Decoud finished his thought with an upward toss of the arm,
silver bars were worth less for his purpose than so much lead,
tone as if she were repelling an undeserved aspersion. "Viola,
leaves of sandal-wood. "I had it in my pocket," he murmured,
years had left her heart to turn into a wall of silver-bricks,
recipient of Martin Decoud's confidences as to his thoughts,
called Viola, a protege of Mrs. Gould. The whole building, which,
silent. So is the plain between the town and the harbour; silent,
we were looking together at the crowd on foot and on horseback,
preconcerted signal for his Cargadores. He ran out immediately,
candles were burning down in their sockets. A large iron nut,
supper. But I remember distinctly he was shrieking for mercy,
Nostromo, with his Cargadores and some Italian workmen as well,
head of it--late in the afternoon, it is true, when the mob,
Ribierist cause became confirmed beyond the shadow of a doubt,
bullocks. Sitting on one of the carcasses, a lepero, muffled up,
Behind him, on the back of the chair from which he had risen,
something to eat, or trying to snatch an hour or so of sleep,
in his head, in the complete collapse of every resolve,
real. All the engineers are out, and have been for two days,
other side of the courtyard. As I sat talking with Nostromo,
Cordillera between us and Montero's victorious army I seemed,
the wounds; at the other, near the stairs, Father Corbelan,
attitude towards the outer world which education, tradition,
trabuco loaded with slugs, of which every one missed him,
was exactly as if there had been two men inside his frock-coat,
him, God only knows why. Only Don Jose hid his face in his hands,
poured out an impassioned appeal to their courage and manliness,
called him The General) intentions were probably not evil,
inflated terms. He seemed fairly safe from being found out,
persuade himself in a grave oration of the clemency and justice,
Juste's measured mouthing monotone go on from phrase to phrase,
"Her eyes blazed with indignation, but as I looked on,
will never do anything for the sake of their passionate desire,
"Late at night we formed a small junta of four--the two women,
Christianity. Later on, the principal European really in Sulaco,
the engineer-in-chief of the railway, came riding up the Calle,
"Ribiera had yielded to the urgent solicitations of his friends,
and had left the headquarters of his discomfited army alone,
ranchero would have perished a long way from Sulaco. That man,
"He had his feet wrapped up in blood-stained rags, a lean,
haggard face, ragged beard and hair, and had walked in limping,
to us, 'that I dared not risk the rolling-stock in the interior,
Government transport in the bay and are filling her with troops,
people; this 'Imperium in Imperio,' this wealth-producing thing,
intellectually. A passion that is not like the passions we know,
Concession. And he defers to her because he trusts her perhaps,
with him to return--to play my part in the farce to the end, and,
"I recognized something impassive and careless in its tone,
not what I expected. It was only an old woman, an old lace-maker,
"I said that it could not be otherwise, surely. He walked on,
muttering to himself. 'Si, si, without doubt, without doubt; and,
the people who make use of him are with their money. At least,
Dazedly Decoud observed that he must have fallen sound asleep,
"The doctor says there is no hope," Mrs. Gould spoke rapidly,
inquiring glance he only shook his head and went outside at once,
Mrs. Gould's carriage waiting on the road, with the yellow-faced,
portly Ignacio apparently dozing on the box. By his side Basilio,
"And there is nothing more for her?" asked the old man,
"No. Not on earth," said the doctor, with his back to him,
the top he paused, broad shouldered, narrow hipped and supple,
than herself. Gian' Battista was an attractive young fellow,
profound quietness of personality which, like a serene twilight,
Old Giorgio, in profound ignorance of his wife's views and hopes,
success. He was escaping from her, she feared. She was practical,
"You refuse to go?" she gasped. "Ah! you are always yourself,
since?  I am no longer an insignificant youth. A good name,
Gould and Don Martin, preceded by the horseman bearing the torch,
the corner of a hard wood table near the candlestick, his seamed,
shaven face inclined sideways, his arms crossed on his breast,
fireplace, where the pot of water was still boiling violently,
"You gamble too much, and never say 'no' to a pretty face,
"What bargain would your worship have made?" asked Nostromo,
"Illustrious Capataz, for taking the curse of death upon my back,
if the silver of the mine had been the emblem of a common cause,
Martin Decoud called out from the lighter, "Au revoir, messieurs,
wind failed, then fanned up again, but so faintly that the big,
sound of blubbering, a sound a sorrowing man could make,
"This is overpowering," he muttered. "Do we move at all,
peered for the islands. There was not a hint of them to be seen,
a matter of course, into his hands.  It was more dangerous,
away from the land till we grow weak, and perhaps mad, and die,
given to me like a deadly disease. If men discover it I am dead,
Reflect that, even by giving up the treasure at the first demand,
we would not be able to save our lives.  Do you understand this,
his way; but tonight the gulf, under its poncho of clouds,
hours without intermission. He had had no rest, very little food,
was thrown out of all this into a dark gulf, whose very gloom,
"True. It is but a mile or so, I suppose. Rest your arms, senor,
ride off again for a priest. Father Corbelan, who is fearless,
head out of his hiding-place to-night to save a Christian soul,
the account of the Capataz's impatience. Sometimes they paused,
Decoud had heard nothing. He expressed his incredulity.  However,
Senor Hirsch, the hide merchant from Esmeralda. Nostromo, too,
had recognized him. And they gazed at each other across the body,
that he should be thrown overboard, as he seemed to be dead,
stomach of an honest man. Hirsch didn't stay to hear any more,
lot of empty casks. After a while some people came along,
undertone, as if speaking to himself, remarked that, after all,
way, like an inanimate and useless object--like a block of wood,
himself with ingenuity and courage; but you have heard his tale,
Decoud had no answer to make. It was not a position for argument,
It was evident that Hirsch could not be spoken to, reasoned with,
overweening vanity of his companion. It was direct,
invisible vessel, whose position could not be precisely guessed,
sheets of paper, with the heavily-printed heading,
times over his shoulder as he wrote; but the Senor Administrador,
finished. He had waved it away firmly. It must have been scorn,
At that moment, as if by way of comment upon Nostromo's words,
"They are trying for a sight of the Isabels," muttered Nostromo,
showing his white teeth all the time. But one of my Cargadores,
with the desperate character of the affair.  Whatever happened,
as death, did anything to betray the nearness of the lighter,
no more than that, Nostromo said, gnashing his teeth audibly),
the Capataz knew very well; and he, too, meant, in his own way,
capable. Nostromo muttered, "True, true! You are a politician,
floating in a boat, exposed to thirst, hunger, discovery,
regrets, it was too late! It could not be done without noise,
restless. Was it possible, he asked himself, that the steamer,
good many officers of the troops garrisoning the province,
ardour for reform before Don Jose Avellanos, casting frank,
instinct. At times, in solitude, he had his moments of ferocity,
caused those gentlemen to neglect their civil duties altogether,
file of soldiers from the post office to the Commandancia,
observed going in and out at the great door of the Commandancia,
where the horses of the orderlies doze under their heavy saddles,
drunkenness.  He clasped the telegraphist close round the neck,
laying hands on so much wealth made them absurdly foolhardy, and,
helmsman fled from the wheel. He took refuge in the engine-room,
her search for the Isabels. The group could not be made out, and,
head, asked himself how long it would be before she drew past,
again; and immediately he heard another lot of shrieks for help,
when the lighter heeled over unsealed his lips.  His shriek,
guide. Where the ravine opens between the cliffs, and a slender,
scanty two hours before daylight.  The existence of the treasure,
generosity. It is looked for from the Capataz of the Cargadores,
those girls that boast of having opened their doors to my knock,
the people would say. They are queer, the good people of Sulaco,
down in charge of fifty peons working like one man with ropes,
make for Zapiga. It is a settlement of thieves and matreros,
any one whatever; even in the officers of the Company's steamers,
"As some men are said to be," Decoud pronounced, inscrutably,
with a regular splash.  Decoud, incorrigible in his scepticism,
Nostromo ceased baling, and, as if struck with a sudden thought,
indubitably saved the silver of the mine. Not only this silver,
not equal to. Ask the foreign signori. I, a man of the people,
you to Sulaco.  Come, senor. Your reputation is in your politics,
stood up again the noisy wash about the Hermosa sounded far away,
separated, to prepare for the coming of the Monterist regime,
the railway staff, collecting their Basque and Italian workmen,
marched them away to the railway yards, leaving the Custom House,
sent their penetrating aroma into his nostrils. Their light,
there.  Then, on the flank of their workmen they tramped on,
"Withdrawing your people from the harbour?" said the doctor,
mob along the Campo Road towards Rincon. The two deputies also,
"Costaguana for the Costaguaneros," interjected the doctor,
"Well, I am one of them," Charles Gould's voice sounded, calmly,
"That man is calmness personified," he said, appreciatively,
seemed to cling to his battered personality limping about Sulaco,
Tome mine he became a recognized personality. He was recognized,
conspiracy except in the diseased imagination of the Tyrant; and,
that accusation. The procedure had dragged on for years,
the Gould Concession, treated with reverent awe by the miners,
engineer-in-chief, with an army of workers under his orders,
countrymen. His austere, old-world Republicanism had a severe,
cavern of banditti with the price of your ransom in your pocket,
at which you shrug your shoulders is perfectly correct,
banditti is always at the mercy of the first imbecile ruffian,
for his life, with a proclamation in his pocket, to a rough,
called a general.  It sounds like a comic fairy tale--and behold,
in Sta. Marta I was struck by the way all those journalists,
once down the coast. For the military chief there was Barrios,
The two men remained still and silent till the murmurs ceased,
driven her into despair. You know," went on the doctor,
hesitatingly, "women are so very unaccountable in every position,
course, I suppose so. But as a man, don't you know, Gould,
don't know why the devil he should be faithful to you, Gould,
Mitchell, or anybody else.  He knows this country well. He knows,
his pack to begin life on. And do you think that Gamacho, then,
would have ever become a hero with the democracy of this place,
shouted like mad, lifting his clenched fist right above his head,
I felt, too, the dangers of the gentlemen of the Amarilla Club,
several nights owing to the disturbances. I stood stock still,
very few yards from him. Then the low, shuffling, murmuring,
right up the column. Near by a loud voice directed hurriedly,
planks a couple of field guns, dragged by hand, rolled by. Then,
statement of Hirsch, which was so absolutely fatal to his hopes,
him up with several other people he had seen in the Casa Gould,
have been a room occupied by some higher official of the Customs,
the arm, led him to a chair, waved his hand at the room. "Go out,
by the throat. As to Captain Mitchell, the suddenness,
"I demand restitution and apologies," Mitchell thundered at him,
Captain Mitchell had just the time to glance once at the windows,
floor the rifles they had dropped to grapple with the prisoner,
It was true, that when searched for arms in the hall downstairs,
Sotillo advanced one leg and put his arms akimbo.  "It is you,
soldiers!" He pointed at his prisoner a forefinger with a long,
Captain Mitchell, with each of his arms held by a couple of men,
Mitchell declared in a loud voice. "And whatever your purpose,
smoke hung about in the vast gloomy place, the fire crackled,
An officer from the top of the stairs was shouting urgently,
of death, envisaged as an accident to the body alone,
It seems that the party of soldiers had stolen quite close up,
as if paralyzed, but the old husband ran across to the bedside,
admitted to the inner councils of the San Tome Administration,
remarked that the story sounded incredible. Of course, he said,
succeeded in assuming so well a tone of impartial indifference,
detachment from the rest of the Europeans led Sotillo on, till,
best, and if you leave her on shore, first of all it is not fair,
and next she either suffers from it or doesn't care a bit, which,
upon the sea. At this my Sotillo slapped his forehead. 'Por Dios,
yet, I can tell you. To begin with, I won't go without my watch,
the casement of one of the windows, with his eyelids lowered,
hesitated, glanced towards the doctor, who looked up and nodded,
Sotillo hurried on. "But as for me, you can live free, unguarded,
displeased him to be liberated insultingly; but want of sleep,
Europeans, was ready to sell his countrymen and Charles Gould,
of a profound and innocent character. It bordered upon stupidity,
withdrawal of the armed rabble under Senores Fuentes and Gamacho,
was a hasty and risky exodus, and it was said that Hernandez,
general in a memorable last official act of the Ribierist party,
critical state the priest was not aware. Antonia read it, and,
his way of thinking to follow him, withdrew into the corredor,
parliamentary institutions. Seated before a blank sheet of paper,
people, dragging along the bigger children. When Charles Gould,
after leaving the doctor and the engineer at the Casa Viola,
and Antonia walked on each side of the improvised stretcher,
emissary, with his ragged beard all streaked with grey, and high,
Antonia, dry-eyed, got in by the side of the stretcher, and,
gate in the lighted patch of the street. One of their neighbours,
The houses of the vast Plaza were lost in the night.  High up,
"Si, senor," he muttered, hoarsely, "I and two or three others,
It was to him, too, that Hernandez came after he had deserted,
the scared faces of people standing aside in the road, sunk deep,
roof of grass had been set on fire by accident, and the flames,
roaring viciously, lit up an open space blocked with horses,
hand, staggered against the front wheel. Two young girls,
"Has not the master of the mine any message to send to Hernandez,
all into soldiers.  Look at those oligarchs fleeing for life,
turned about like one man as Charles Gould passed, and shouted,
against the rim of the fountain, fingering a guitar discreetly,
while two girls of the lower class, standing up before him,
practicante endeavoured to conceal his guitar hastily; the girls,
More dangerous to the wielder, too, this weapon of wealth,
which his wife was no longer the sole mistress of his thoughts,
something of his father's imaginative weakness, and something,
with marked gravity, leading the way. This was Don Juste Lopez,
hour. They saw him, too, waved their hands to him urgently,
other's eyes strayed dully over the tiled floor of the corredor,
by deputations from the Cabildo, which is the Municipal Council,
elbow on the balustrade. He shook his head a little, refusing,
Charles Gould stopped before the sad bewilderment of the faces,
for those men, putting all their trust into words of some sort,
bodies--the Cabildo, the Consulado--would be coming, too,
examination of his wounded. He gazed down upon each in turn,
the doctor, with his special conception of this political crisis,
castle resounded with the clanking of leg-irons, sounds of blows,
as distinctly as ever. He remembered that priest at night,
at the end of a long black table, behind which, in a row,
calling heaven to witness of his innocence, till he burst out,
And he could not forget Father Beron with his monotonous phrase,
his prison, and so motionless that the spiders, his companions,
dragged himself past the guard-room door, one of the soldiers,
ceaseless trembling agitated his bent body, all his wasted limbs,
the imaginative exaggeration of a correct feeling. It was also,
drawing-room of the Casa Gould on that morning, exclaiming,
Mrs. Gould, her colour heightened, and with glistening eyes,
dazzling snow-edge of Higuerota, had precipitated the delicate,
imaginative satisfaction which other minds would get from drama,
head? The eyes of Mrs. Gould, watching her husband's profile,
inaccessible. To send off a boat to Cayta was no longer possible,
The women, screaming "Misericordia!" ran right into the room,
doorway in an instant--mozos from the stable, gardeners,
all the belfries in the town in order to welcome Pedrito Montero,
of all colours, complexions, types, and states of raggedness,
torrent of rubbish, a mass of straw hats, ponchos, gun-barrels,
with an enormous green and yellow flag flapping in their midst,
equestrian statue of the King dazzlingly white in the sunshine,
towering enormous and motionless above the surges of the crowd,
the use of intelligence awakened wonder and respect.  Stratagems,
reflection that the fundamental causes were the same as ever,
Before all, Pedrito Montero, taught by his European experience,
under the arms of Senores Fuentes and Gamacho. In that posture,
very sure of laying his hands upon Decoud. On his left hand,
of yellow fangs in a grin of stupid hilarity.  On his right,
The crowd stared literally open-mouthed, lost in eager stillness,
remained fascinated by the orator's action alone, his tip-toeing,
the confines of the crowd, like flames running over dry grass,
"It is all the work of Gamacho and his Nationals;" and then,
Pedrito Montero looked with disgust at the absolutely bare floor,
opinion was that war should be declared at once against France,
shallow pretences, aimed at robbing poor people of their lands,
leperos, flinging about the corners of their dirty white mantas,
clear sea of grass, and the precipitous range of the Cordillera,
stamp sheds and the houses of the mine appeared dark and small,
face of the rock, Don Pepe's figure kept on descending steadily,
the houses, not a stone's throw from the frontier bridge,
rich now.  That was very good. More he did not know, and,
alcalde of the first village. The man rode off, and Don Pepe,
striding slowly in the direction of a little wooden belfry,
palm. On his reddish-brown face, worn, hollowed as if crumbled,
to a legally constituted commission of patriotic citizens,
stout person with an effect of a gaudy bathing robe, stood by,
for the people of the town and the Campo. His yellow, round face,
of paternal scorn.  He had been marrying, baptizing, confessing,
inhale with a strong snuffling noise a large quantity of snuff,
was a serious asset in the country's finance, and, what was more,
necessary by the labours and the pomps of his entry into Sulaco,
untidy bed, to the neglect of his duties, menial or otherwise,
the splendour of the old Intendencia, the magnificent hangings,
furniture huddled up in the middle of the vast apartment,
reminded him, with the brother of the master of the country,
interfere with the enjoyments of the people. And above the roofs,
in severe black waited in the main gallery, formal and helpless,
waiting for their audience. The one from the Provincial Assembly,
overtopped by the big face of Don Juste Lopez, soft and white,
if in a dense cloud. The President of the Provincial Assembly,
so well have a nightmarish meaning in this country.  Liberty,
"They will try to tamper with him," the doctor suggested,
Charles Gould, looking at the doctor steadily, shook his head,
to Mrs. Gould, whom he met in the corridor.  "The thing is done,
west. The doctor, holding a straight course for the Custom House,
water of the harbour. A long tongue of land, straight as a wall,
dripping, into the main quadrangle of the old fort; and there,
corruption. When the man got up the vulture hopped away in great,
The darkness of the sky had descended to the line of the horizon,
beaten as a boy on one of these feluccas by a short-necked,
appear but faintly in retrospect. Under the sense of loneliness,
appeared tolerable. But, what? Return? With bare feet and head,
peaks crowded around the white, misty sheen of Higuerota,
shook his head.  To the left and right, in front and behind him,
finished"--announces calamity and death in the popular belief,
no judgment, he said to himself. It was useless to suppose that,
falling black hair, the wide-browed suffering face raised to him,
whether what they affirmed was not true. Power, punishment,
uproariously. He wondered what had upset them so much, and,
been drowned by this time. No one would have cared--unless,
a slow drift of smoke. That was the room. He climbed the stairs,
man cast upon one of the walls. It was a shapeless,
the Capataz, advancing a couple of steps out of his corner,
presence on shore, unless after many days, would, he believed,
It rendered him timorous for a moment before that enigmatic,
his retreat. He got away down the stairs with perfect success,
It was very simple. For an infinitesimal fraction of a second,
man standing, as he had imagined him, with his back to the door,
constrained, toppling attitude--the shoulders projecting forward,
look at the rigid legs, at the feet hanging down nervelessly,
"I told you well, senor doctor," remarked Nostromo at that point,
well of the business. So you need not taunt me. I tell you what,
hopeless fervour which had no time to surprise Dr. Monygham,
saved themselves by swimming as you have done," the doctor said,
doctor, impelled to risky action by his loyalty to the Goulds,
of hope and reward, made Dr. Monygham's thinking, acting,
soul, withered and shrunk by the shame of a moral disgrace,
irresolution, anger, and mistrust. He was the first to break it,
He did not quite finish what he meant to say, breaking off short,
"It was the worst darkness of the Golfo," the Capataz assented,
mental reservations. Surprise and rage rendered him speechless,
to it. He is not fit for Costaguana, and that is a fact,
upon the situation. And the Capataz, listening as if in a dream,
that. He had told him everything.  But I tell you what it is,
Fuentes, our new Gefe Politico, and himself, too. Only, he says,
"You have?" the Capataz de Cargadores repeated cautiously. "Well,
This is what Dr. Monygham said in answer to Nostromo's remark,
would resume his tramping in savage aloofness. His hat,
officers, crowding the window giving the view of the town gate,
Senor Fuentes, on entering upon his functions of Gefe Politico,
audacious nostrils appeared mean and pinched.  The velvety,
addressed the surprised envoy of Senor Fuentes in a deadened,
"muy valliente" colonel. A wavering wildness of expression,
uneasiness. The brave Esmeralda Regiment held the harbour,
half-delirious invalid under the inquisitive stare of the envoy,
would not open them again, lying perfectly still, deaf, dumb,
voice, "a man of many teeth--'hombre de muchos dientes.' Si,
worship is beholding the finest body of officers in the Republic,
high gate of a dismal barn. He raised himself in his stirrups,
sort of catalogue of perfections: "Generous, valorous, affable,
at that stage of the expedition. He had seen himself triumphant,
open to his choice. Alas! How different! Distracted, restless,
The colonel gave his orders, and presently the miserable Hirsch,
broad armchair, hat on head, knees wide apart, arms akimbo,
hands tied behind his back, swaying a little in front of Sotillo,
entered the torture-chamber where his sword, horsewhip, revolver,
on the landing presented arms, and got in return a black,
venomous, unsteady glance, which, in reality, saw nothing at all,
"Speak, thou Jewish child of the devil! The silver!  The silver,
A slight quiver passed up the taut rope from the racked limbs,
Esmeralda, hung under the heavy beam perpendicular and silent,
up. For a word, for one little word, he felt he would have knelt,
stare of those fixed eyeballs starting out of the grimy,
he say? How could he explain? Ideas of headlong flight somewhere,
like a scarecrow, walked round the body of the late Senor Hirsch,
hasten the retirement decided upon in the afternoon. Sinister,
for a time in the dismal solitude of the unfinished building,
Their voices, which without rising had been growing quarrelsome,
In a completely changed tone he pointed out to the Capataz that,
"I understand you all!" cried the other with a violent movement,
relented with a contemptuous fairness.  "Of course," he went on,
The doctor breathed freely. "Listen, Capataz," he said,
not be prudent to part in anger from his companion. The doctor,
get the treasure back for you to give up to Sotillo, or Pedrito,
and the threatening tone. To their eyes, accustomed to obscurity,
"None of your friends could reward you and protect you just now,
"Well, we would trust your courage and your sense.  And you, too,
The doctor started. "I say that you must be true to yourself,
He slipped off the table, listening intently. The Capataz, too,
A low exclamation had escaped Nostromo.  The doctor waited,
not even sure about. If it comes off you get the benefit. If not,
"This has the merit of being the truth," the doctor said,
too great there. He has no divers, but he has a ship, boats,
Nostromo had paused; then began again in a changed tone, sombre,
pursuit. At the bottom of the charred stairs he had a fall,
by the exaltation of self-sacrifice; a reasonable exaltation,
House, before he managed to seize his arm from behind, roughly,
He stopped at loss for words, feeling fagged out, powerless,
"I am betrayed!" muttered the Capataz to himself; and the doctor,
"You are a man of infinite resource, Capataz," said Dr. Monygham,
Turning swiftly, and catching the doctor by the shoulders,
"How can I go in?" Nostromo seemed to ask himself in a low,
to fasten their horses to, Nostromo did not move, as if he, too,
The enthusiastic and severe soul of Giorgio Viola, sailor,
approached the grave passion of that time but the deep,
silence that seemed invincible till the Capataz de Cargadores,
support, as if the mere presence of that man who was loyal,
Old Viola walked out of a dark corner, and, without a word,
long, soft eyelashes, which gave to the upper part of his fierce,
mine--Nostromo. The sailor whom I discovered, and, I may say,
Regarded by the O. S. N. Company as an old and faithful servant,
flower stalls piled up with masses of gorgeous colouring,
footing in the Casa Gould, he led his privileged old bachelor,
hour, with his own gig, manned by a smart crew in white and blue,
jerky periods, with slight sweeps of his short, thick arm,
A historical woman! Opposite--Casa Gould. Noble gateway. Yes,
Seventeen shares--quite a little fortune to leave behind one,
under that very gateway, sir, with some young engineer-fellows,
that side of the Plaza? Compania Anzani, a great general store,
specific crime that the deputy Gamacho, commanding the Nationals,
down, and the miners of San Tome, all Indians from the Sierra,
rolling by like a torrent to the sound of pipes and cymbals,
never be seen again. The miners, sir, had marched upon the town,
Thus Captain Mitchell would talk in the middle of the Plaza,
kneeling female figure, black or all white, with a veiled head,
The marble medallion in the wall, in the antique style,
memory of Martin Decoud, his betrothed Antonia Avellanos.' Frank,
plate-glass shop-fronts; our biggest daily. Conservative, or,
intellect, sir. The Democratic party in opposition rests mostly,
Italians settled here on the railway lands, dismissed navvies,
uniform, middle-aged caballeros from the Campo--sallow, little,
members in remembrance of the fight against Gamacho's Nationals,
"Look at this man in black just going out," he would begin,
right and left with no end of formality; then with animation,
man in black by her side, with a high white collar and a scarred,
snarly face, was Dr. Monygham, Inspector of State Hospitals,
railway yards, and got admission to the engineer-in-chief, who,
for the sake of the Goulds as much as for anything else,
Monterist lines outside Cayta. The history of that ride, sir,
out of the Albergo d'ltalia Una, climb into the cab, and then,
sir, that engine seemed positively to leap clear of the house,
regiment, standing by, unsheathed his sword with a shriek: 'Die,
man, a large shipper by our line, came to see me on business,
by the hair of his head, smile at his cringing.  'Yes,' he says,
few, mostly Anglo-Saxon, skilled in the art of, as the saying is,
annihilated mentally by a sudden surfeit of sights, sounds,
would hear a voice, familiar and surprising in its pompousness,
to the Costaguana-Sulaco War. How the United States cruiser,
Powhattan, was the first to salute the Occidental flag--white,
purple slippers and a velvet smoking-cap with a gold tassel,
"He appeared to me in this very room like a haunting ghost,
warmth of feeling and a touch of wistful pride. "You may imagine,
"'Senor,' says he, looking at me in a slow, inquisitive manner,
"'My name is known from one end of Sulaco to the other,' he said,
experiences in the woods of Los Hatos, had an interview with him,
too.  Wanted to hear about Decoud: what they said, what they did,
transports, and within an hour's steaming from Sulaco. Barrios,
consent from Barrios the transport swept out of her course,
transports, scattered haphazard over a mile or so in the offing,
"Let you? What a conceited fellow that is," bantered the General,
overboard. That empty boat, coming out to meet him mysteriously,
rid of his boots and coat in the water. He hung on for a time,
from the messenger.  In fact, Barrios, talking with Nostromo,
The Capataz frowned: and in the immense stillness of sea,
felt the ingots inside.  There they were. One, two, three. Yes,
In the face of the open gulf, the sun, clear, unclouded,
mystery of self-immolation consummated far from all mortal eyes,
"He might simply have cut his hand," he muttered.  "But,
reflection the forms of the Three Isabels. He never saw it,
For some good and valid reasons beyond mere human comprehension,
individuality.  It had merged into the world of cloud and water,
the range of his vision; and, as if to escape from this solitude,
tense, thin cord to which he hung suspended by both hands,
The sun was two hours above the horizon when he got up, gaunt,
the fascination of all that silver, with its potential power,
be set afloat.  He had eaten a little every day after the first,
stood behind him warm with sunshine, as if with the heat of life,
silence appeared again before him, stretched taut like a dark,
thought that this one had been forgotten by all mankind. Then,
died. But he knew the part he had played himself.  First a woman,
And four ingots! Did he take them in revenge, to cast a spell,
valour, the toil, the fidelity of the poor, over war and peace,
Capataz looked down for a time upon the fall of loose earth,
invested in the San Tome mine; and Dr. Monygham had grown older,
Consolidated Mines (whose territory, containing gold, silver,
Europe and the United States of America.  Intimate of the casa,
triple row of old orange trees surrounded the whole. Barefooted,
brown gardeners, in snowy white shirts and wide calzoneras,
bow on an immaculate shirtfront.  Under a shady clump of trees,
of his collar, he devoured her stealthily with his eyes, which,
Mrs. Gould sighed. And as two friends, after a long separation,
appeared visibly in what, by contrast with former carelessness,
in our hotel in London. He comported himself with great dignity,
Nostromo is getting older--though he is not changed. And,
Mrs.  Gould. She had brought her uncle over to see dear Emilia,
heartily everybody who approached Mrs. Gould with any intimacy,
the ground, and Antonia, graceful and rigid in her chair,
his Eminence's extended hand, Dr. Monygham, looking after them,
Not all day, though. She is up towards five in the afternoon,
when our Nostromo, whenever he is in harbour with his schooner,
"I am afraid of being overwhelmed by too much gratitude. However,
benefactress"; in black-eyed Linda's voluble, torrential,
white-throated, fair Giselle's adoring upward turn of the eyes,
which then glided towards him with a sidelong, half-arch,
charge of was sunk, Nostromo, on leaving the Company's service,
fair one. Ramirez was warned off. Father Viola, I am told,
men's attentions. Ramirez was not the only one, let me tell you,
waiting for her on purpose. I was there by the merest chance,
upon Ramirez, who seemed out of his mind. It was a strange sight,
"I feel I have a duty towards these girls," said Mrs.  Gould,
Through the garden gate emerged Basilio, grown fat and sleek,
the gateway between the garden and the patio with measured steps,
San Tome mountain hanging over the Campo, over the whole land,
house she loved so well! Incorrigible, the last of the Corbelans,
imminent detection. He had to visit the Great Isabel in secret,
suspicion even by a day's delay.  Sometimes during a week's stay,
Tome. His courage, his magnificence, his leisure, his work,
her love for Gian' Battista. He could see it would be violent,
secret spot of his life; that life whose very essence, value,
light there. A light! He saw it shining upon disgrace, poverty,
on Azuera--weighed heavily on the independent Captain Fidanza,
Fiercely whiskered and grave, a shade less supple in his walk,
harbour; he talked with people in a cafe or two in his measured,
to keep up in the increased size and varied population of Sulaco,
Captain Fidanza, unpicturesque, but always a little mysterious,
in a thousand." With Giorgio established on the Great Isabel,
Directly his schooner was anchored opposite the New Custom House,
"You are welcome like a son," the old man declared, quietly,
He got up slowly. His beard, unclipped since Teresa's death,
desired--but the shining spectre of the treasure rose before him,
were betrothed," he said, steadily, in his level, careless,
at each other. Then the old man ceased; and Linda, motionless,
else. I was yours. Nothing is changed. The world belongs to you,
Suddenly Linda rushed at her sister, and seizing her head,
"And you, little one, pray not to the God of priests and slaves,
white throat, which had the invincible charm of things young,
captivity to the sky and water. Nothing else.  Sky and water. Oh,
"Mercy of God! How violent you are, Giovanni," she said,
iron laid across the entrance of a world sombre as a cavern,
She raised her embroidery to conceal the lower part of her face,
charm of her body, the promising mysteriousness of her indolence,
came instinctively upon her lips shaped for love and kisses,
restrain himself any longer.  While she shrank from his approach,
crying. Then the incomparable Capataz, the man of careless loves,
that name. But there was no one approaching their black shapes,
sister Linda, betrothed to-day to Giovanni--my lover! Giovanni,
Released, she hung her head, let fall her hands. The altar-cloth,
Giovanni, carry me off to-night, from my fear of Linda's eyes,
She disengaged herself gently. He got up and looked down at her,
head. He could not see her now. She had vanished into a long,
their betrayal. For he had been betrayed--he said--deceived,
treasure arose, standing by her side like a figure of silver,
"Tell him I would not stay," and was gone suddenly from her,
She did not wait in vain. The man whose soul was dead within him,
"You have come back to carry me off. It is well! Open thy arms,
slave of the unlawful treasure. The light in the room went out,
while ashore that day, he had met the doctor with the evil eye,
It was a warning to be cautious. He stopped some distance away,
contemplating gaze and continued to speak, looking at her work,
"Give up the palazzo, Giovanni, and the vineyard on the hills,
shame, lying on the carved and lettered stone of Teresa's grave,
of the Viola heroism. Ready to faint with terror, she only said,
in a lazy voice, "Madre de Dios! Are you going to eat me alive,
The invincible candour of the gaze, raised up all violet and dew,
with kisses of pity and love. And suddenly they became empty,
"No?" said Linda, through her clenched teeth. "Is he not? Well,
"I shall say nothing--never any more--to anybody," cried Linda,
diamonds, containing not a lamp, but some sacred flame,
temples. They would meet. They would meet. And she knew where,
answer; but as she was rushing, distracted, round the house,
going. The tree under which Martin Decoud spent his last days,
directed to where the shade was blackest.  "Like a thief he came,
hand from his arm, firm and steady like an arm of stone, and,
great dreams of wealth, considered, loved, respected, honoured,
that when they got round to the low side of the Great Isabel,
very silver. She had been corrupted by her fears at that time,
evening costume, this woman, full of endurance and compassion,
the low sobs of Giselle Viola, kneeling at the end of the bed,
powder might have been saved. The honour was safe. . . . Senora,
was nothing of importance. Let it go. Up, Nostromo, the faithful,
"Now, Mrs. Gould," he said, almost brutally in his impatience,
immaculate republican, the hero without a stain. Slowly,
of the Senor Administrador of the San Tome mine. And Mrs. Gould,
"Senora, he loved me. He loved me," Giselle whispered,
There was no one with the wounded man but the pale photographer,
late on the wharf, had heard from a negro belonging to a lancha,
"Have you any dispositions to make, comrade?" he asked,
Dr. Monygham, going out in the police-galley to the islands,
be aware of her presence, but when, losing her forced calmness,
coming to the ground together with his daughter. His excitement,
horizon. Like a black speck upon the shining panes, Linda,
Mala to Azuera and away to the bright line of the horizon,
